Graduate Education, Office of; Records ua410
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Records of J. Fredericks Volkwein, Assistant Dean, 1966-1977; 4; 0.66 cubic ft.
  - Schedules for Graduate Program Reviews, 1972-1975 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Department of Instruction, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Meeting the Needs of Doctoral Education, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence - Daniel H. Murray, 1973; 1974; 1975; Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - State Education Department Correspondence, 1973-1977; Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Women's Studies Program, 1974 November 29 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Office of Institutional Research- Annual Report, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Romance Languages, 1974; 1975; 1976; Undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - University Libraries, 1974; 1975; 1976 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Graduate Studies - Administrative Self-Study, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Records of Robert McFarland, Assistant Dean, 1964-1991; 5; 3 cubic ft.
  This series consists of records created by Robert McFarland, who served in various positions at the University, including Assistant Dean of Graduate Studies. Topics addressed in the series generally relate to the administration of graduate programs. Materials include daily correspondence with students, Deans, and academic departments, graduate thesis and dissertation abstracts and transmittals, correspondence with the State Department of Education regarding program registration and review, and materials from search committees for various Deanships and other administrative positions.
  - Thesis Abstracts, 1964-1970 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Master's Thesis Abstracts and Transmittals, 1965-1969 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Department of English, 1966; 1971 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Flinton, Edgar W., 1966-1971 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Daily Correspondence - Robert McFarland, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - School of Library Science, 1967; 1971; 1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence - Saimond, Paul, 1967-1973 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Graduate Student Association, 1967-1970; 1975; Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Peterson's Guides Correspondence, 1967; 1969; 1973-1981 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Daily Correspondence - Robert McFarland, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Department of History, 1968-1972 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Department of Economics, 1968; 1971; 1972; Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Department of Romance Languages, 1968; 1972; Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Graduate School of Public Affairs, 1968-1973 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Program Review and Revision, 1968-1971; 1976; 1981-1985; 1991; Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Daily Correspondence - Robert McFarland, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence - Kuusisto Alan, 1969; 1970 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - NDEA Fellowship Materials, 1969; 1970 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence - Cowling, Vincent, 1969; 1971 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence - O'Reilly, Charles, 1969; 1970; 1971 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence - Wheeler, Paul, 1969; 1971 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Department of Atmospheric Science, 1969; 1970; 1971 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence - Colman, Charles, 1969-1972 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Graduate Program Revisions, 1969; 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence - Volkwein, J. Fredericks, 1969-1974 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Outline and Procedure for Graduate Program Proposals, 1969; 1971; 1974 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Council of Graduate Schools, 1969; 1970; 1978; Undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Miscellaneous Materials, 1969-1986 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Daily Correspondence - Robert McFarland, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Political Economy, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Department of Rhetoric and Public Address, 1970; 1971 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Dissertations, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Department of German, 1970; 1971; Undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Department of Sociology, 1970; 1971; 1972 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Foundations of Education, 1970; 1972 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Department of Reading, 1970; 1971; 1972; Undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence - Benezet, Louis T., 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Daily Correspondence - Robert McFarland, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Search Committee For Director of Research, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Search Committee For a Graduate Dean, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Department of Afro-American Studies, 1971; Undated (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Department of Anthropology, 1971; 1972 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Department of Psychology, 1971; 1972 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - School of Criminal Justice, 1971; 1972 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Dissertations (1 of 2), 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Dissertations (2 of 2), 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Department of Art, 1971; 1972; Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - School of Social Welfare, 1971; 1972; Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence - Salkever, Louis, 1971; 1972; 1973 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence - Sirotkin, Phillip, 1971; 1972; 1973 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Department of Chemistry, 1971; 1973 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Department of Geology, 1971; 1973 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Bilingual Education, 1971; 1972; 1973; Undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence - Registrar's Office, 1971-1974 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Regional Cross-Registration, 1971-1974 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Search Committee Staff Manual, 1971; 1976; 1978-1980; Undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Daily Correspondence - Robert McFarland, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Italian Studies, 1972; Undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Israeli Programs (1 of 2), 1972; 1973 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Israeli Programs (2 of 2), 1972; 1973 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Long Range Planning Task Force, 1972; 1973 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Graduate Policies, 1972; 1974; 1976; 1978-1980; Undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Daily Correspondence - Robert McFarland, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Graduate Program Review Policies and Procedures, 1973; 1977-1979; 1982-1983; Undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Proposal for a Mathematics /M.B.A. Programs, 1974 November (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Daily Correspondence - Robert McFarland, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Projects-John W. Shumaker, 1974; 1977; 1980-1985; Undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Ad Hoc Publications Group, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Daily Correspondence - Robert McFarland, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - State University College at Geneseo, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Select Committee on Academic Program Priorities, 1975; 1976 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Daily Correspondence - Robert McFarland, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Search Committee for Vice President of Academic Affairs, 1976; 1977 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Public Information, 1976; 1977; 1978 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - SED-SUNY Lawsuit, 1976-1978 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - SED Correspondence, 1976; 1978-1982 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Terminated Programs, 1976; 1978-1987; 1989-1990; Undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - State Education Department Reviews to Date, 1977 August (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Daily Correspondence - Robert McFarland, 1977; 1978 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Graduate Faculty, 1977; 1978 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Office of Graduate Studies and Office of Summer Sessions Professional Staff, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Office of Program Registration and Review, 1977; 1978 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Required Annual Reports - SED and SUNY, 1977; 1978; Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence - Program Review and Registration, 1977-1984 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - State Education Department Reviews, 1977-1979 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence - State Education Department, SUNY (1 of 2), 1977-1985; Undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence -State Education Department, SUNY (2 of2), 1977-1985; Undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Department of Anthropology, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Sixth Year Campus Certificate Program in Library and Information Science, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Public Information, 1978; 1979; 1980; Undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Library, 1978-1981 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Promotion Review Panel, 1978-1982 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Office of Program Registration and Review, 1978; 1988; 1989; 1990; Undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - SED Conference, 1979 February 8-1979 February 19 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Daily Correspondence - Robert McFarland, 1979-1984 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Academic Program Development, 1979-1985 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Certificate Programs, 1980; 1984-1987; Undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Program Registration Materials, 1981; 1982; Undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence - State Education Department, 1981-1989; Undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Office of Program Registration and Review, 1982; 1988; Undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Search Committee for Vice President for Research and Educational Development, 1983-1985 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Search Committee for Vice President for Research and Educational Development, 1983-1985 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Committee on Psychology Programs, 1984-1985 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Search for Assistant to the Vice President for Research and Educational Development, 1984-1985 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Graduate Bulletin, curriculum changes, 1984-1986; 1989 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Advisory Committee to Strengthen the Department of African and Afro-American Studies, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Search Committee for the Vice President for Research and Dean of Graduate Studies, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Undergraduate Programs, 1985; 1986 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Planning Documents, College of Science and Mathematics, 1985; 1991 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Middle States Review, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Search Committee for Executive Vice President for Academic Affairs, 1987 December 21 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Search Committee for Provost of Rockefeller College/Director of Rockefeller Institute of Government, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Academic Policy Group Minute, 1988-1990 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Search Committee for the Dean of Undergraduate Studies, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Records of Richard Farrell, Assistant Dean, 1977-1990; 6; 0.66 cubic ft.
  This series contains records created by Richard Farrell, who served as Assistant Dean of Graduate Studies. Much of the material consists of correspondence, meeting minutes, and supporting materials for the Enrollment Management Committee. Additional topics include: student surveys, program accreditation and evaluation, and five-year planning documentation.
  - Graduate Student Surveys, 1977; 1979-1981; 1983; Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Enrolled Graduate Student Survey, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Non Enrollment Survey, 1978; 1979 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Non Enrollment Survey, 1979; 1980 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Middle States Accreditation, planning, 1980-1981; 1984; 1986; 1988-1989; Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - English for International Teaching Assistants, 1984; 1985; 1986 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence - Walt Gibson, 1985; 1986 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - School of Business - Admissions, 1985; 1986 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - School of Public Health Services, 1985; 1986; Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Graduate Assistantships Education, 1986; 1988; 1989; 1990 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Enrollment Management Committee, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Enrollment Management Committee, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Enrollment Management Committee, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Enrollment Management Committee - Enrollment Data, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Enrollment Management Committee - Graduate Minority Recruitment and Retention Subcommittee, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Enrollment Management Committee, 1988; 1989 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Enrollment Management Committee - Graduate Minority Recruitment and Retention Subcommittee, 1988; 1989 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Task Force on Library Construction, 1988; 1989 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Enrollment Management Committee, 1988; 1989; Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Enrollment Management Committee, 1988; 1989; Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Enrollment Management Committee - Graduate Admissions and Recruitment Audit, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Five Year Plan, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Enrollment Management Committee - Minority Enrollment, 1989; Undated (Box 2, Folder 10)